<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
	<name>Arrest and Release</name>
	<author>1trickPonyta</author>
	<packageId>arrestandrelease.1trickPonyta</packageId>
	<modVersion IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">1.2.1</modVersion>
	<supportedVersions>
		<li>1.3</li>
		<li>1.4</li>
		<li>1.5</li>
		<li>1.6</li>
	</supportedVersions>
	<description>
Arresting your colonists during mental breaks only to immediately release them for the chance at a different mental break has become a bit more micro since the 1.3 update.

Introducing the Arrest and release command, which allows you to arrest a colonist and immediately release them in just one click. 

- You don't need to have a prison to use this command, just a room that *could* be a prison if you were to place a sleeping spot inside.
- The arrestee also doesn't drop their weapon or their inventory so you don't have to micro-manage them to pick everything back up.

This mod tries to stay true to the vanilla mechanics. You shouldn't be able to do anything you couldn't do before; you just don't have to click as much. As such: 

- If the arresting pawn drops the arrestee before the arrest and release is complete, the arrestee will become a prisoner and drop their inventory as usual.
- After the command completes, the arrestee will still get the Was imprisoned mood debuff.
- The arrestee will lose any ideology roles they hold.

=== Updates ===
06/14/2025: Updated to 1.6
11/05/2024: Arrestee now reclaims their bed after the arrest and release action is complete.
03/21/2024: Updated to 1.5
10/26/2022: Updated to 1.4
09/20/2021: Arrestee always loses ideology role because of new ritual requirement.

=== Credits ===
Mod icon: twitter.com/mouse_draws
	</description>
	<url>https://github.com/1trickPonyta/ArrestAndRelease</url>
	<modDependencies>
		<li>
			<packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
			<displayName>Harmony</displayName>
			<steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
			<downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
		</li>
	</modDependencies>
</ModMetaData>